<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">

  <title><![CDATA[davidekline]]></title>
  <link href="http://davidkline.github.io/atom.xml" rel="self"/>
  <link href="http://davidkline.github.io/"/>
  <updated>2013-09-03T14:31:44-05:00</updated>
  <id>http://davidkline.github.io/</id>
  <author>
    <name><![CDATA[David Kline]]></name>
    
  </author>
  <generator uri="http://octopress.org/">Octopress</generator>

  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[The Story So Far]]></title>
    <link href="http://davidkline.github.io/2013/09/03/the-story-so-far/"/>
    <updated>2013-09-03T12:43:00-05:00</updated>
    <id>http://davidkline.github.io/2013/09/03/the-story-so-far</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>The problem with escalation is that it makes you take previous accomplishments for
granted. My peers in the PhD program have achieved the same things I have; while our
individual stories have differences in detail, our baseline experiences, accomplishments
and sensibilities are much the same. This tends to make one less
appreciate their own achievements, because it appears everyone else has done the same shit.</p>

<p>Had I taken a job in Houston, I suppose I
would be in a similar situation: one where the entry requirements are high enough to make
me nothing special. But I feel like moving 1300 miles northeast is
more of a reboot than taking Highway 6 over to Houston, buying a 2014 Chevy truck, and renting a
shitty apartment.</p>

<p>I may
have been things down south but they have been left behind; today I am just another grad
student from a far away land. The novelty is exciting. My concern is that I have devalued
what I used to consider important in order to chase notoriety, money and power.</p>

<p>The question is, what do I consider important? What exactly have I devalued, at least for
the time being?</p>

<ul>
<li>Family</li>
<li>Friends</li>
<li>Hobbies</li>
</ul>


<p>I still talk to my family and friends, thanks to technology. What I can&rsquo;t do is talk to
them in person. My hobbies are mostly intact, with the exception of my absent, once-perennial
companion, a 1989 Nissan. Now it&rsquo;ll sit and rot until I have the space for it up here.
So I&rsquo;m missing face-to-face interaction with my closest friends and family&hellip; and my car.
That doesn&rsquo;t seem too bad when I put it that way, especially considering I am not required
to be here forever.</p>

<p>What am I getting in return?</p>

<p>An education. Or more accurately, an escalation of my education. I&rsquo;m already highly educated
relative to the other seven billion people on the planet. So I&rsquo;m getting more, just to rub
it in their faces. Apparently.</p>

<p>But I&rsquo;m not pursuing an advanced degree for money, power or notoriety. I&rsquo;m pursuing it because
it&rsquo;s the next step of my development. I didn&rsquo;t agonize over the implications of learning
to read when I did so in kindergarten; I now don&rsquo;t agonize over the implications of staying
in school.</p>

<p>I hate feeling this way. How is what I currently am not good enough? At what point did I
decide I wasn&rsquo;t in charge of my own future and that I must continue on, checking perceived
requirements off of my to-do list?</p>

<p>I don&rsquo;t know. But I&rsquo;m here now, and fuck it, let&rsquo;s see what happens next.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Relaunch]]></title>
    <link href="http://davidkline.github.io/2013/08/29/relaunch/"/>
    <updated>2013-08-29T11:09:00-05:00</updated>
    <id>http://davidkline.github.io/2013/08/29/relaunch</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>In case you haven&rsquo;t already noticed, I have relaunched this blog using a static blog generator—<a href="http://octopress.org">Octopress</a>.
The design of the blog is something I cobbled together by modifying the freely available <a href="http://zespia.tw/Octopress-Theme-Slash">Slash theme</a>
and takes advantage of <a href="http://www.google.com/fonts">Google Fonts</a>. I am using <a href="http://pages.github.com">GitHub Pages</a> to host the site.</p>

<p>The previous blog is still active <a href="http://superjoyluck.blogspot.com">at its Blogger domain</a>. I will move over select posts
in the coming weeks.</p>

<p>—David</p>

<p>P.S. I just completed a move from Texas to Michigan. I&rsquo;ll be starting classes next week at U of M Ann Arbor (Go Blue!).
If I didn&rsquo;t get a chance to say goodbye to you properly before moving 1300 miles away, I&rsquo;m very sorry.
Moving cross country is difficult and I didn&rsquo;t plan my departure very well. Catch me on <a href="http://www.twitter.com/davidekline">Twitter</a> or send me an email or text
if you want to catch up and we haven&rsquo;t already.</p>

<p>Till next time&hellip;</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Two Doors]]></title>
    <link href="http://davidkline.github.io/2012/06/24/two-doors/"/>
    <updated>2012-06-24T14:53:00-05:00</updated>
    <id>http://davidkline.github.io/2012/06/24/two-doors</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>Overdrawn. Laid off. Looking for anything for the time being. Hourly. Streaks of street lights, halogen, as money leaves the tail pipe and eyelids droop down. Back home.</p>

<p>The alarm clock doesn’t need to be alarming. It can display the time. It doesn’t need to remind anyone of anything.</p>

<p>Phone ringing. Maybe he should have gotten up earlier. Stumbling over cans on the way to the bathroom, phone pinched to his shoulder.</p>

<p>Can I come in today? Yeah, yeah, I can make it.</p>

<p>Fucking ties. The fabric things. Ones you wear on necks.</p>

<p>Driving surface streets now: traffic lights. Water temperature a little hot.</p>

<p>Didn’t know where to park.</p>

<p>Finally inside. Two sets of doors. Air curtain. Nice place. Leased.</p>

<p>Too much experience&mdash;why are you here?</p>

<p>Didn’t matter. They’d call.</p>

<p>Back outside, through the two doors. Looking for his car, has two doors.</p>

<p>Found it. Couldn’t chirp the horn. Not keyless.</p>

<p>Driving back, surface streets, the loop, outside the perimeter.</p>

<p>Shitty rented place.</p>

<p>Squalor.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
</feed>
